Salvador Luria Papers 1923-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1938-1992; 15.5 linear feet
  - Hook, Ernest B., 1976 (Box 15)
  - Hopkins, Nancy Haven, [197-] (Box 15)
  - Hopper, Paul T., 1974 (Box 15)
  - Horecker, B.L., 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    See also Ser.I, Albert Einstein College of
  - Horiuchi, Tadao, 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Horowitz, Ed, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Hortado Vega, Juan José, 1982 (Box 15)
  - Hotchin, John E., 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hotchkiss, Rollin, 1956, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Housman, David E., 1985 (Box 15)
  - Howard, Bruce David, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Howe, Martha M., 1971, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Hu, Benjamin, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Huang, Alice S., 1972 (Box 15)
  - Hubácek, J., 1962-1963 (Box 15)
  - Hull, Robert W., 1961 (Box 15)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1968, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Hunter College, 1981-1986 (Box 15)
    See also Ser.IIa, same title
  - Hurvitz, Bob, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Hurwitz, Charles, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Hurwitz, Jerard, 1965, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Iino, Tetsuo, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Imanishi-kari, Thereza, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Indiana University, 1956, 1970, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Ingraham, John L., 1962-1963 (Box 15)
  - Inselburg, Joseph W., 1974-1982 (Box 15)
  - Institut de la Vie, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Institut Pasteur, 1977-1978, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Institute for Scientific Interchange, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Institute of History of Medicine and Medical Research, 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Institute of Society, Ethics, and the Life Sciences, 1973, 1975 (Box 15)
  - International Cell Research Organization (Box 16)
    Some in French and Italian
    Buzzatti-Traverso, Adriano A.
    Cairns, John
    Gros, François
    Hayes, William
    Hedén, C.-G.
    Kepes, Adam
    Klein, George
    Maaløe, Ole
    Mazia, Dan
    Pardee, Arthur B.
    Porter, J.R.
    Siddiqi, Obaid H.
    - Folder #1, 1963-1969 (Box 16)
    - Folder #2, 1970-1974 (Box 16)
    - Folder #3, 1975-Mar. 1976 (Box 16)
    - Folder #4, Apr. 1976-1983 (Box 16)
  - International Confederation for Disarmament and Peace, 1973 (Box 16)
  - International Conference on Biological Membranes, 1966-1985 (Box 16)
  - International Conference on Single-Cell Protein, 1967 (Box 16)
  - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, 1974 (Box 16)
  - International Congress for Biochemistry, 1957 (Box 16)
  - International Congress for Microbiology, 1970 (Box 16)
  - International Congress of Biochemistry, 1979 (Box 16)
  - International Congress of Genetics, 1956 (Box 16)
  - International Convocation of the Fund for Peace, 1974 (Box 16)
    Commoner, Barry
  - International Laboratory of Genetics and Biophysics, 1963-1973 (Box 16)
    Buzzatt-Traverso, Adriano A.
    See also Ser.I, Laboratorio Internazionale di Genetica e Biofisica
  - International Periodontic-Prosthodontic Conference, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, Inc., 1981 (Box 16)
  - International Symposium on the Dynamics of Virus Infections, 1958 (Box 16)
  - Iseki, Shoei, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Ishidate, Kohei, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Israeli Institute for Biological Research, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Isselbacher, Eric Michael, 1974, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Isselbacher, Jody, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Isselbacher, Karen, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
  - Isselbacher, Kurt, 1969, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Itano, Harvey, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Ivánovics, George, 1960-1961 (Box 16)
  - Iyer, Venkatram N., 1956-1957 (Box 16)
  - Jackson, Richard W., 1956 (Box 16)
  - Jacob, François, 1980 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.I, Fondation Royaumont
  - Jacobs, Nicholas Joseph, [195-] (Box 16)
  - Jacoby, Kurt, 1962 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.I, Academic Press, Inc.
  - Jaenisch, Rudolf, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Jaffin, Henry M., 1969-1973, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Jencks, William P., 1971 (Box 17)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1971, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Jetten, Anton M., 1978-1982 (Box 17)
  - Jewish Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Jewish Currents, 1972 (Box 17)
  - John, E. Roy, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1955-1956 (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Edward M., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Howard, 1971, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Johnson and Johnson, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Jones, Elizabeth W., 1967, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Jordan, Elke, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Journal of Bacteriology, 1957-1988 (Box 17)
    Silver, Simon
  - Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Journal of Infectious Diseases, 1960 (Box 17)
    Moulder, James W.
  - The Journal of Medicine and Philosophy, 1976 (Box 17)
  - The Journal of Membrane Biology, 1968-1987 (Box 17)
  - Journal of Molecular Biology, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Journal of Theoretical Biology, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Jukes, Thomas H., 1963 (Box 17)
  - Kaback, H. Ronald, 1970-1976, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Kabat, Jonathan P., 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Kaczorowski, Gregory, 1976, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Kagan, Jerome, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Kahlon, P.S., 1970 (Box 17)
  - Kaiser, A. Dale, 1960-1962, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Kalckar, Herman M., 1958-1982 (Box 17)
  - Kallos, John, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Kalnay Rivas, Eugenia, 1977, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Kamarck, Michael E., 1974-1982, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Kamen, Martin D., 1960 (Box 17)
  - Kameyama, Tadanori, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Kaminskas, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Kaneko, Takichi, 1957-1958 (Box 17)
  - Kaplan, Albert S., 1954-1971 (Box 17)
  - Kaplan, Henry S., 1959 (Box 17)
  - Karlström, O., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Karmel, Ilona, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Karol, Eduardo A., 1969 (Box 17)
  - Karreman, George, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Kass, Leon, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Katchalski, Ephraim, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Katz, Milton, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Katz, Solomon H., 1975 (Box 17)
  - Kauffmann, F., 1958, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Kaufman, Bernard, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Kaufman, Beth Shapiro, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Kaufman, Harriet Enid, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Kaufman, Herbert, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Kayalar, Celik, 1975-1989 (Box 17)
  - Kean, Marie-Louise, 1977, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Keen, Arnold J., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Kelemen, Mary V., 1957 (Box 17)
  - Kellenberger, Eduard, 1954-1963 (Box 17)
  - Kellenberger, Grete, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Kelner, Albert, 1949 (Box 17)
  - Kempf, J.E., 1956 (Box 17)
  - Kendrew, John C., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, Christina Kay, 1971-1984 (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, Edward M., 1965-1977 (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, Eugene P., 1965 (Box 17)
  - Kennell, David E., 1960-1963 (Box 17)
  - Kepes, Adam, 1960, 1982, 1984 (Box 17)
    -See also Ser.I, International Cell Research
    -See also Ser.III, A Farewell
  - Kerry, John, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Kessler, Wolfgang (Box 17)
    See Ser.I, Koch, Egmont R.
  - Keynan, Alexander, 1961-1978 (Box 17)
    -See also Ser.I, Hebrew University
    -See also Ser.I, Israeli Institute for Biological Research
  - Keynes, Richard D., 1975-1977 (Box 17)
  - Khorana, H. Gobind, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Kilson, Martin L., 1973 (Box 17)
  - Kim, W.S., 1976 (Box 17)
  - Kimball, Paul Clark, 1967 (Box 17)
  - King, Donald West, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - King, Jeffrey, 1973 (Box 17)
  - King, Jonathan, 1973, 1975 (Box 17)
  - King, Mary E., 1956 (Box 17)
  - Király, Z., 1957 (Box 18)
  - Kirk, Samuel A., 1969 (Box 18)
  - Kirsten, Werner H., 1968 (Box 18)
  - Kistiakowsky, Vera, 1972, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Klein, George, 1962-1988 (Box 18)
  - Klein, Harold P., 1956 (Box 18)
  - Klein, Richard, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Kleinman, Steve, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Klug, Aaron, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Knight, C.A., 1959, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Knopf, Paul, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Kobbe, Bruni, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Koch, Arthur, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Koch, Egmont R., 1973 (Box 18)
    Kessler, Wolfgang
  - Koerner, James F., 1961 (Box 18)
  - Kohler, Robert E., Jr., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Kojiro, Katsuto, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Kolko, Gabriel, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Kondo, Sohei, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Konisky, Jordan, 1980-1984 (Box 18)
  - Kos, Edward S., 1957 (Box 18)
  - Kozloff, Lloyd M., 1949, 1956-1957, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Kucera, Sonia, 1956 (Box 18)
  - Krebs, Hans A., 1972 (Box 18)
  - Kreiling, Janet, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Krichevsky, 1959-1960 (Box 18)
  - Krieg, David R., 1957-1960 (Box 18)
  - Krieger, Monty, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Kung, Hsiang-Fu, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Kunkee, Ralph, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Labarre, Robert Lawrence, 1982-1983, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Laboratorio Internazionale di Genetica e Biofisica, 1962-1969 (Box 18)
    See also Ser.I, International Laboratory of Genetics and Biophysics; Hebrew University.
  - Laffler, Thomas, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Landman, Otto, 1956-1962, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Lang, Serge, 1978, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Länger, Peter, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Langer, Robert Samuel, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Lanni, Frank, 1954-1960 (Box 18)
    Lanni, Yvonne T.
  - Lanni, Yvonne T., 1954-1955 (Box 18)
    See also Ser.I, Lanni, Frank
  - Lasagna, Louis, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Lasko, Paul, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Latarjet, Raymond, 1954 (Box 18)
  - Layzer, David, 1972, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Lazdunski, Claude, 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Lebowitz, Jacob, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Leder, Philip, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Lederberg, Esther, 1953 (Box 18)
    See also Ser.I, Lederberg, Joshua
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1949-1973 (Box 18)
    Lederberg, Esther
    Morse, M.L.
  - Lederberg, Seymour, 1956-1961 (Box 18)
  - Lehmann, P., 1966 (Box 18)
  - Lehninger, Albert L., 1965 (Box 18)
  - Leitenberg, Milton, 1965-1981 (Box 18)
  - Leive, Loretta, 1970-1972 (Box 18)
  - Lengyel, Peter, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Lennox, Edwin S., 1954-1969 (Box 18)
    Puck, Theodore T.
    -See also Ser.I, Cohn,
  - Gruppo Lepetit, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Letelier, Orlando, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Levialdi, Andrea, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Levine, Lawrence, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Levine, Myron, 1955-1972 (Box 18)
  - Levinthal, Cyrus, 1956-1988, n.d. (Box 18)
    Stent, Gunther S.
  - Levinthal, Jeana D., 1984 (Box 18)
  - Levy, Bernard, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Levy, David, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Levy, Edward R., 1986 (Box 18)
  - Levy-Montalcini, Rita, 1957, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Lewis, Anthony, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Lewis, Herman, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Lewontin, R. C. (Richard Charles), 1985; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 18)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Darwin, Charles; History of biology, especially genetics; Publication -- Not in Our Genes
  - L'Héritier, Ph., 1957 (Box 18)
  - Liberman, Alvin M., 1974 (Box 18)
  - Librairie Armand Colin, 1974-1975 (Box 18)
  - Lichten, Michael, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Life, 1956 (Box 18)
  - The Lilly Research Laboratories, 1951-1952 (Box 18)
  - Lin, Fang-Jen, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Lipski, Jan Jozef, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Little, Bill, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Litvac, Anna, 1940-1941, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Liu, Stephen C.Y., 1976-1982 (Box 18)
  - Lodish, Harvey Franklin, 1970 (Box 19)
  - Long Island Biological Association, 1956-1959 (Box 19)
  - Lorch, Lee, 1954-1957 (Box 19)
  - Losick, Richard Marc, 1970-1976 (Box 19)
  - Louisiana State University, 1956 (Box 19)
  - Lourie, Alan D., 1984 (Box 19)
  - Lown, Bernard, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Lu, Ponzy, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Lubin, Martin, 1960-1968 (Box 19)
  - Luck, J. Murray, 1968 (Box 19)
  - Luirink, Joen, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Luria, Zella (Box 19)
    See Ser.I, The Boston Globe
  - Lusby, Monica Riley, 1959-1960 (Box 19)
  - Lusk, Joan Edith, 1970-1977 (Box 19)
    Plate, Charles A.
  - Lwoff, André, 1954-1968, n.d. (Box 19)
    See also Ser.I, Institut Pasteur
  - Maaløe, Ole, 1954-1963 (Box 19)
  - Maas, Werner, 1955, 1963 (Box 19)
  - Maccacaro, Giulio A., 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - McCaffrey, Ronald P., 1977 (Box 19)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, 1968, n.d. (Box 19)
    See also Oversized
  - McCarthy, Richard D., 1969 (Box 19)
    See also Ser.I, Schlesinger, R. Walter
  - McClintock, Barbara, 1978, 1982; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 19)
    Biographical and personal data; Lectures, public speaking; Lederberg, Joshua
  - McClung, L.S., 1956-1958, 1979 (Box 19)
    See also Ser.I, American Society for
  - McConnell, Harden M., 1974, 1977 (Box 19)
  - McConnell, R.A., 1973 (Box 19)
  - McCormick, John W., 1968 (Box 19)
  - McDonald, Douglas G., 1982 (Box 19)
  - McDowell, Banks, 1965 (Box 19)
  - McFall, Elizabeth, 1961 (Box 19)
  - McGovern, George, 1971-1972 (Box 19)
    -See also Ser.I, Bengelsdorf, Irving
  - McGrady, Patrick M., 1958, 1963 (Box 19)
    -See also Ser.I, American Cancer Society,
  - Machlup, Stefan, 1960 (Box 19)
  - McKee, G.S., 1963 (Box 19)
  - MacLeod, Colin M., 1958 (Box 19)
  - Macmillan Company, 1962 (Box 19)
  - McReynolds, 1970 (Box 19)
  - Magasanik, Boris, 1959-1982 (Box 19)
  - Magni, Giovanni, 1956, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Maio, Joseph J., 1956 (Box 19)
  - Mäkelä, Olavi, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Mandel, Ernest, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Mandel, Manley, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
    Franklyn, Naomi
    -See also Ser.I, Dushman, Miriam B.
  - Maness, Patricia F., 1982 (Box 19)
  - Maniatis, George, 1970 (Box 19)
  - Manly, Kenneth, 1970, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Mansfield, Michael, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Manzone, Bruno, 1955-1956 (Box 19)
  - Maramorosch, Karl, 1957 (Box 19)
  - March to Jerusalem, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Marcovich, Herbert, 1970, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Marcus, Joseph, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Marcus, Menashe, 1974, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Marcus, Philip I., 1957 (Box 19)
  - Margolin, Paul, 1982-1985 (Box 19)
  - Margolis, Frank L., 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Markert, Clement L., 1954 (Box 19)
  - Lucille P. Markey Charitable Trust, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
  - Markovitz, Alvin, 1962, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Marks, Paul, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Marmur, Julius, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Martonosi, Anthony N., 1972-1982 (Box 19)
  - Masini, Giancarlo, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Maruyama, Masao, 1968 (Box 19)
    The Boston Globe
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1974-1989 (Box 19)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1956-1992 (Box 19)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Loyalty Oath Fund Committee, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Technology and Culture Seminar, 1971-1973 (Box 20)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. The Equal Opportunity Committee (Box 20)
    - Folder #1, 1979-Mar. 1980 (Box 20)
    - Folder #2, Apr. 1980-Mar. 1981 (Box 20)
    - Folder #3, Apr. 1981-1985 (Box 20)
  - Mateles, Richard I., 1973 (Box 20)
  - Matney, Thomas S., 1963 (Box 20)
  - Matsubara, Kenichi, 1986 (Box 20)
  - Matsubara, Kerick, 1988 (Box 20)
  - May, Carl W., 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Mayr, Susanne, 1955-1956 (Box 20)
  - Mazia, Dan, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Medawar, P.B., 1956 (Box 20)
  - Medical Tribune, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Mehler, Jacques, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Melechen, Norman E., 1960-1962 (Box 20)
  - Mellencamp, Gail, 1987 (Box 20)
  - Melman, Seymour, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Meselson, Matthew Stanley, 1957-1958 (Box 20)
  - Methods in Virology, 1963-1969 (Box 20)
  - Metz, Charles W., 1964 (Box 20)
  - Meuth, Mark L., 1971 (Box 20)
  - Meynell, G.G., 1959 (Box 20)
  - Miathe, Santina L., 1963 (Box 20)
  - Michigan State University, 1957 (Box 20)
  - Microbial Genetics Bulletin, 1954-1971 (Box 20)
    Adler, Howard I.
    Witkin, Evelyn M.
  - Microsensory Newsletter, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Mill, Dennis C., 1974 (Box 20)
  - Miller, C. Phillip, 1956 (Box 20)
  - Miller, Harriet, 1958 (Box 20)
  - Miller, Oscar L., Jr., 1970 (Box 20)
  - Milner, Esther, 1972 (Box 20)
  - Mirsky, Alfred E., 1956-1957 (Box 20)
  - Mitchell, Peter, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Mitsuhashi, S., 1976 (Box 20)
  - Mizobuchi, Kiyoshi, 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - Moleculon Biotech, Inc., 1985-1988 (Box 20)
  - Monadnock Summer Lyceum, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Monod, Jacques, 1957-1976; 39.0 Item(s) (Box 20)
    Some in French-See also Ser.I, Collège de France
    Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Conferences and symposia; Fellowships, assistantships; Jacob, Francois; Molecular genetics; Political issues; Publication; Requests for reprints; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- France; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Monroy, Alberto, 1967, 1982, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Montedison, 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - Moore, Walter J., 1986 (Box 20)
  - Morgan, Councilman, 1957 (Box 20)
  - Morgenstern, Jay, 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Morison, Elting E., 1974 (Box 20)
  - Morowitz, Harold J., 1968 (Box 20)
  - Morse, Bradford, 1965 (Box 20)
  - Morse, M.L. (Box 20)
    See Ser.I, Lederberg, Joshua
  - Morse, Wayne, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Mortlock, Robert P., 1958, 1960 (Box 20)
  - Mosberg, Henry I., 1978 (Box 21)
  - Mosig, Gisela, 1967-1972 (Box 21)
  - Motulsky, Arno G., 1974 (Box 21)
  - Moulder, James W., 1956-1959, 1972 (Box 21)
    See also Ser.I, Journal of Infectious
  - Mueller, Lavonne, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Muller, H. J. (Hermann Joseph), 1956-1962; 8.0 Item(s) (Box 21)
    Biographical and personal data; Bolton, Ellis T.; Carlson, Elof Axel; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Genetics; Glass, Bentley; Lectures, public speaking; Political issues
  - Muller, Kenneth J., 1970 (Box 21)
  - Muller, Thea, 1972-1974 (Box 21)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Murray, Robert G.E., 1956 (Box 21)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Nagel de Zwaig, Rosa, 1976-1981 (Box 21)
  - Najjar, Victor A., 1956 (Box 21)
    See also Ser.I, Vanderbilt University
  - Nakamura, Masahiro, 1957 (Box 21)
  - Nanney, David L., 1958-1959 (Box 21)
  - Nason, Alvin, 1971-1974 (Box 21)
  - The Nation, 1969 (Box 21)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1955-1986; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Business; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Human genetics; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Political issues; Publication; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder #1, 1955-Apr. 1972 (Box 21)
    - Folder #2, May 1972-1986 (Box 21)
  - National Cancer Institute, 1979 (Box 21)
  - National Collegiate Association for the Conquest of Cancer, 1970 (Box 21)
  - National Commission on Smoking and Public Policy, 1976-1977 (Box 21)
  - National Committee for the Defense of Academic Rights, 1980 (Box 21)
  - The National Foundation, 1950-1957, 1972 (Box 21)
  - National Genetics Foundation, 1971 (Box 21)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1958-1987 (Box 21)
  - National Medal of Science, 1991 (Box 21)
  - National Portrait Gallery, 1992 (Box 21)
  - National Research Council (Box 21)
    - Folder #1, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Folder #2, 1975, 1985 (Box 21)
  - National Research Council. Board of Research on the Effects of Radiation, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box 22)
    Committee activities; Human genetics; National Research Council; Political issues; Radiation genetics
    - Folder #1, 1981-1982 (Box 22)
    - Folder #2, 1983-1985 (Box 22)
    - Folder #3
  - National Science Foundation, 1957-1985 (Box 22)
  - National Symposium on Genetics and the Law, 1974-1975 (Box 22)
  - Natural History, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Nature, 1962, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Neihardt, Frederick C., 1970, 1986 (Box 22)
  - New England College English Association, 1972-1973 (Box 22)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences, 1957-1983 (Box 22)
  - New York Heart Association, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - The New York Review of Books, 1973-1977 (Box 22)
  - The New York Times, 1961-1985 (Box 22)
  - The New York Times Book Review, 1974, 1980 (Box 22)
  - The New York Times Magazine, 1975, 1983 (Box 22)
  - New York University, 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - The New Yorker, 1979, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Newlon, Michael, 1972-1980 (Box 22)
  - Nichols, Irene (Box 22)
    See Ser.I, Saletan, Eugene
  - Ninfa, Alexander J., 1988 (Box 22)
  - Nisman, Ben, 1960 (Box 22)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1969, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Nobel Prize, 1969-1981 (Box 22)
    Honors -- Nobel Prize
  - Nobel Prize--Congratulations, 1969-1970; 8 folders (Box 22)
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Nobel Prize; Delbruck, Max; Hershey, Alfred Day; Honors -- Nobel Prize
    - Folder #1, 15-16 Oct. 1969 (A-M) (Box 22)
    - Folder #2, 16 Oct. 1969 (N-Z), 17 Oct. 1969 (A-E) (Box 23)
    - Folder #3, 17 Oct. 1969 (F-P) (Box 23)
    - Folder #4, 17 Oct. 1969 (R-Z)-19 Oct. 1969 (Box 23)
    - Folder #5, 20-21 Oct. 1969 (Box 23)
    - Folder #6, 22-27 Oct. 1969 (Box 23)
    - Folder #7, 28 Oct. 1969-20 Jan. 1970 (Box 23)
    - Folder #8, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Noble, David F., 1979-1987 (Box 24)
  - Nogueira, Christine P., 1990 (Box 24)
  - Nomura, Masayasu, 1962-1984 (Box 24)
  - Northeastern University, 1981 (Box 24)
  - W.W. Norton and Company, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Novick, Aaron, 1956-1963, 1984 (Box 24)
    See also Ser.I, Stahl, Franklin W.
  - Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, 1984-1985 (Box 24)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1949, 1957-1958; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 24)
    Hollaender, Alexander
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Conferences and symposia; Delbruck, Max; Hollaender, Alexander; Lederberg, Joshua; Molecular genetics; Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Radiation genetics; Stern, Curt; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Oh, Ok Jang, 1956-1960 (Box 24)
  - Olby, Robert Cecil, 1974; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 24)
    History of biology, especially genetics; Publication -- The Path to the Double Helix
  - Omori, Gendo, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Omura, Satoshi, 1973 (Box 24)
  - O'Neill, Thomas P., 1973, 1985 (Box 24)
  - The Open University, 1974-1979 (Box 24)
  - Oppenheim, Amos B., 1970 (Box 24)
  - Orear, Jay, 1961 (Box 24)
  - The Oregon Health Sciences University, 1982 (Box 24)
  - Orent, Joel, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Orgel, Leslie, 1963 (Box 24)
  - O'Rourke, Ann Marie, 1963 (Box 24)
  - Orskov, Frits, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Ortega, Manuel, 1963 (Box 24)
  - Ortiz, Priscilla, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Osaka University, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Osborn, Mary Jane, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Osborne, Brian I., 1980, 1988, 1991 (Box 24)
  - Ose, Earl, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Osgood, Charles E., 1966 (Box 24)
  - Ostrer, Harry, 1971-1974 (Box 24)
  - Overath, Peter, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Ovi, Alessandro, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Owen, Frances L., 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - Ozawa, Yoshikiro, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Ozeki, Haruo, 1964 (Box 24)
  - Padan, Etana, 1969-1970 (Box 24)
  - Paigen, Kenneth, 1962-1963 (Box 24)
  - Painter, Robert B., 1957 (Box 24)
  - Pappenheimer, A.M., Jr., 1957 (Box 24)
  - Pardee, Arthur B., 1959-1975 (Box 24)
  - Park, James T., 1971, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Park, Soon Jae, 1986 (Box 24)
  - Parker, R.F., 1956 (Box 24)
  - Parks, T.N., 1974 (Box 24)
  - Passman, Leigh, 1980, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Pathobiology Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 24)
  - Paton, Martha Jean, 1954-1956 (Box 24)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1957-1965; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 24)
    Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Political issues -- Atomic weapons; Radiation genetics; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.)
  - Payne, Fernandus, 1960-1961, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Peck, Sidney, 1977-1981 (Box 24)
  - Pei, Nivin, 1982 (Box 24)
  - Pereira da Sila, Luiz, 1981 (Box 24)
  - Perlman, David, 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Perrin, David, 1961 (Box 24)
  - Perry, Ruth, 1986 (Box 24)
  - Perspectives in Virology, 1961-1982 (Box 24)
  - Perutz, Max F., 1962 (Box 24)
  - Pfeiffer, John, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Phillips, William D., 1971 (Box 24)
  - Photochemistry and Photobiology, 1960-1966 (Box 24)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, Inc., 1981 (Box 24)
  - Pigiet, Vince, 1986 (Box 24)
  - Pigman, Ward, 1956 (Box 24)
  - R. Piper and Company, Verlag, 1971, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Pirie, Antoinette (Box 24)
  - Pitkin, John R., 1970 (Box 24)
  - Plate, Charles A., 1968-1987 (Box 24)
    See also Ser.I, Lusk, Joan E.
  - Porter, J.R., 1970 (Box 24)
  - Portnoy, Stephen, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Powledge, Tabitha M., 1978 (Box 24)
  - Pratt, David, 1961 (Box 24)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1957 (Box 24)
  - Presbyterian-St. Luke's Hospital, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Pressman, B.C., 1967 (Box 24)
  - Price, Alan R., 1972 (Box 24)
  - Priestino, Donaldo H., 1972 (Box 24)
  - Princeton University, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Pritchard, R.H., 1963 (Box 24)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 1968-1987 (Box 25)
  - Protoplasmatologia, 1953-1958 (Box 25)
    some in German
  - Providence College, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Ptashne, Mark, 1967-1971 (Box 25)
  - Puck, Theodore T., 1949, 1974 (Box 25)